Jermaine Rogers Collection ARC.0058
Library and Archives
Jermaine Rogers Posters
2003-2005
ARC.0058
Library and Archives
4.0 Linear feet (1 shared flat file drawer)
The Jermaine Rogers Posters span the years 2003 to 2005. The collection consists of 18 concert posters for various bands by artist, Jermaine Rogers. Bands include ...And You Will Know Us By the Trail of Dead, The Cure, Jane's Addiction, and Queens of the Stone Age. The collection provides a sampling of Rogers' artistic work for various concerts in the United States. Seen in a broader context, the collection provides insight to how alternative rock bands promoted their shows in the early 2000s, and the bands that played during that era.
Access Restrictions
Collection is CLOSED.
Custodial History note
The Jermaine Rogers Posters were received by the Rock and Roll Hall of Fame and Museum, Inc. as a gift from Jermaine Rogers on June 14, 2005.
Scope and Contents
The Jermaine Rogers Posters are arranged chronologically.
Biographical Note
Jermaine Rogers is an artist and painter located in Brooklyn, New York and best known for his work in the field of modern rock poster art. Rogers began creating posters in 1994, and it became a full-time job in 1996. He has designed over eight hundred posters for performers such as Radiohead, Neil Young, Tool, and Weezer.
Rogers also has corporate clients like Verizon, Sony, and Budweiser. His work has appeared in various publications, including New Musical Express, Esquire, and Entertainment Weekly.
Sources
“About.” JERMAINEROGERS.COM. Accessed February 22, 2011. http://www.jermainerogers.com/about.html.
--And You Will Know Us by the Trail of Dead (Musical group); A.F.I. (Musical group); Audioslave (Musical group); Auf der Maur, Melissa; Blue October (Musical group); Burden Brothers; Burning Brides (Musical group); Coheed and Cambria (Musical group); Cooper Temple Clause (Musical group); Copeland (Musical group); Cure (Musical group); Curiosa Festival; Darkness (Musical group); Deftones (Musical group); Denali (Musical group); Drums and Tuba (Musical group); Dälek (Musical group); Falcon. (Musical group); Further Seems Forever (Musical group); Galactic (Musical group); Head Automatica (Musical group); Jane's Addiction (Musical group); Mogwai (Musical group); Morrison, Jim, 1943-1971; Muse (Musical group); Octopus Project (Musical group); Perfect Circle (Rock group); Poison the Well (Musical group); Queens of the Stone Age; Rapture (Rock group); South by Southwest Music and Media Conference (SXSW); Sparta (Musical group); Sunshine (Musical group: Czech Republic); Throw Rag (Musical group); Tiger Named Love (Musical group); Wildhearts (Musical group); Alternative rock music; Audioslave (Musical group). Love; Graphic artists; Morrison, Jim. Wake up; Posters; Rock concerts; Rock music--Posters
- ...And You Will Know Us By the Trail of Dead, 2003 January 31-2003 February 1; 34.5" x 22.5" (Drawer-folder FF.1.2-5, Object 1)
  Artist's Proof
- Galatic, Drums and Tuba, 2003 February 20; 21" x 16.5" (Drawer-folder FF.1.2-5, Object 2)
  Limited Print Run
  15/75
- Queens of the Stone Age, 2003 March 11; 19.5" x 10.25" (Drawer-folder FF.1.2-5, Object 3)
  Gold 17/25
- Mogwai, ...And You Will Know Us By the Trail of Dead, Dälek, 2003 September 15; 24" x 18" (Drawer-folder FF.1.2-5, Object 4)
  52/175
- ...And You Will Know Us By the Trail of Dead, Mogwai, Octopus Project, A Tiger Named Love, The Falcon, 2003 September 16; 24" x 18" (Drawer-folder FF.1.2-5, Object 5)
  36/175
- Deftones, Poison the Well, Denali, 2003 November 5; 20" x 20.25" (Drawer-folder FF.1.2-5, Object 6)
  71/200
  Museum Accession Number
  A2005.31.5
- Jane's Addiction, Burden Brothers, Blue October, 2003 December 21; 33" x 13" (Drawer-folder FF.1.2-5, Object 7)
  6/200
- A.F.I., Coheed and Cambria, 2004 March 12; 21.25" x 18" (Drawer-folder FF.1.2-5, Object 8)
  90/250
  A2005.31.4
- South by Southwest Music and Media Conference (SXSW), 2004 March 17-2004 March20; 34.5" x 21" (Drawer-folder FF.1.2-5, Object 9)
  35/200
- The Darkness, The Wildheart, 2004 April 11; 29.5" x 19" (Drawer-folder FF.1.2-5, Object 10)
- A Perfect Circle, Burning Brides, 2004 May 29; 31" x 21.5" (Drawer-folder FF.1.2-5, Object 11)
- Curiosa Festival, 2004 August 15; 33.25" x 21.75" (Drawer-folder FF.1.2-5, Object 12)
  8/100
- Sparta, Further Seems Forever, Copeland, Sunshine, 2004; 21"x 18.75" (Drawer-folder FF.1.2-5, Object 13)
  31/325
- Queens of the Stone Age, 2005 March 28; 19.75" x 16.5" (Drawer-folder FF.1.2-5, Object 14)
  75/250
- Queens of the Stone Age, Throw Rag, 2005 April 16; 21" x 28.5" (Drawer-folder FF.1.2-5, Object 15)
- Mars Volta, 2005 April 25; 19" x 26" (Drawer-folder FF.1.2-5, Object 16)
  A2005.31.15
- Audioslave - Love, 2005 May 16; 22" x 33" (Drawer-folder FF.1.2-5, Object 17)
- Morrison, Jim - "Wake Up", 2005; 23" x 30" (Drawer-folder FF.1.2-5, Object 18)
  A2005.31.18